Well we're done with the core of our content provider,
but there's still one more optional method that'll make things
much more efficient. We'll start by hitting Ctrl+O to look
at the functions we can override. It turns out there's
a function called bulkInsert. Anyone out there who has done
database work knows that putting a bunch of inserts into
a single transaction is usually much faster than inserting them
individually. Bulk insert allows us to do just that. The default
implementation just calls insert a bunch of times, but
we can wrap it in a transaction if we implement
it ourselves. We're only going to add support for
weather forecast transactions here, since they're the only we insert
in bulk. We start by calling db.beginTransaction. For each
ContentValues passed in, we insert and update the number of
records inserted. When we're done, we set the transaction
to be successful. Otherwise our records will not be committed,
and then rely on the finally statement to end the
transaction. In the default case, we just call the super
class. Remember, it does the insert, just not optimally. And
that's it, that's all we have to do to implement bulkInsert.